usarugby.org 2018-12-23

# Privacy Policy | USA Rugby

_(Last updated May 20, 2018)_

 _To provide all USA Rugby members (including players, coaches, parents, administrators and officials) with quality service, USA Rugby must collect, process, and use its members’ personal information. At the same time, we want to protect the personal information you provide to us. To underscore USA Rugby’s commitment to protecting your privacy and the value we place on your relationship with us, USA Rugby has adopted the following privacy principles applicable to our handling of your personal information._

## Section 1. Expectation of Privacy

USA Rugby recognizes and respects your expectation of privacy and security for your personal information and we are committed to safeguard the sensitive information about you within USA Rugby.

## Section 2. Use, Collection, and Retention of Information

USA Rugby collects, uses, and retains information about you to help in the development and enhancement of our services; to understand which services will best meet your needs; to provide you with product and service opportunities that we deem interesting or beneficial to you; and to help administer our core business and programs.

Data is primarily collected through the process of becoming or renewing a USA Rugby membership ([https://webpoint.usarugby.org](https://webpoint.usarugby.org/)), and expanded upon when invited to or participating in high performance camps, events, and matches ([https://hiperforms.com](https://hiperforms.com/member/login.php)). Data is also collected from the ticketing agencies of any USA based matches, and through voluntary registration forms created by USA Rugby for event information, media accreditation and service application.

Your data is used exclusively by and for USA Rugby, and is never given or sold to 3rd party organizations. We may serve you tailored and relevant ads both on and off our services, as they pertain to USA Rugby information, updates, and events. We use data about Members for communications promoting membership, engagement and events.

Requests to edit/update/remove your data should be sent to the membership department.

## Section 3. Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)

COPPA, the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act, applies to individually identifiable information about a child that is collected online, such as full name, home address, email address, telephone number or any other information that would allow someone to identify or contact the child. The Act and Rule also cover other types of information — for example, hobbies, interests and information collected through cookies or other types of tracking mechanisms — when they are tied to individually identifiable information.

At this time, USA Rugby requires parental consent for children under the age of 13 to register or provide other information to USA Rugby through the use of the internet website, www.usarugby.org. If, at any time, USA Rugby policy changes to allow for the collection of information from children under the age of 13, the changes will be notified in this document, and additional information will be provided pursuant to COPPA, in the form of: (a) names and contact information of operators employed by USA Rugby to collect this data; (b) types of information and reasons for USA Rugby to obtain this information from children; (c) procedures by which parents can review a child’s personal information.

* * *

###  _CHILDREN 13 & UNDER_

Please pay close attention to the information outlined in this document. You are required to have your parents understanding and consent before you enter any personally identifiable information into any forms on the USA Rugby website.

* * *

###  _PARENTS_

Please be sure to read this Use of Member Information and Privacy Policy. USA Rugby requires your consent prior to any child 13 or under entering any personally identifiable information into the USA Rugby website. Please notify USA Rugby immediately if you have any concerns regarding USA Rugby and COPPA. We encourage parents and guardians to spend time online with their children, and to take an active role to protect the privacy of their children, including but not limited to instructing their children not to disclose any personal information over the Internet without your prior permission. For additional information concerning COPPA, parents and guardians are encouraged to visit [www.coppa.org](http://www.coppa.org/).

## Section 4. Maintaining Accurate Information

Through our procedures and technology, USA Rugby will strive to maintain information about you that is accurate and complete. We will respond to your requests to correct inaccurate information in a timely manner should the need arise, but we reserve the right to ensure that the request to make changes is coming from you. We encourage you to verify periodically that the information we have about you is current and correct.

## Section 5. Limiting Access to Information

USA Rugby has procedures and security measures that restrict access to and disclosure of personally identifiable information to those individuals in our organization with a sound business reason to access such information. USA Rugby employees are subject to background screening, and are instructed about the importance of confidentiality and privacy of customer information. Further, USA Rugby makes every attempt to educate volunteers and other administrators about important privacy considerations.

## Section 6. Security Procedures to Protect Information

We maintain security standards and procedures to deter unauthorized access to confidential information about you. We update technology to improve the protection of our information about you and to assure the integrity of our information. You will be notified immediately of any breaches of security that involve any sensitive personal information.

## Section 7. Disclosing Information

We will share your information only with **(1)** reputable reporting agencies; **(2)** when you (the individual) request or acknowledge the disclosure; **(3)** when the disclosure is required, or allowed by law; and **(4)** when necessary to administer our business, which may include, but is not limited to: _releasing participant contact details to the volunteer administrators and instructors of USA Rugby sanctioned coach_ , _referee and youth education programs_ ; and _releasing participant contact details to volunteer administrators and coaches of all developmental and age grade national team programs_. USA Rugby will only release the minimum amount necessary for communication. Under no circumstance will USA Rugby release social security numbers, except as necessary to perform background checks on youth, high school and collegiate coaches, and then only with individual consent, to a fully qualified security company. Credit card numbers remain encrypted in the USA Rugby Membership and course registration systems and are not visible to employees through that system, and will never be released to any party.

## Section 8. Notification of Changes

Any changes to the USA Rugby Use of Information and Privacy Policy will be updated within this posting, and notification provided through the USA Rugby e-newsletter. We recommend that you review the foregoing policy document periodically to become familiar with it and make yourself aware of any changes.
